<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Roughly Cooking</title>
 <link href="http://roughlycooking.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://roughlycooking.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-09-14T13:54:37-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://roughlycooking.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Roughly Chef</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Vegan substitution for everyday pantry basics</title>
   <link href="http://roughlycooking.com/2014/09/14/vegan-subs/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://roughlycooking.com/2014/09/14/vegan-subs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Understanding the basics of what different types of ingredients do to dough&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Things I have been thinking about&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I want to continue using chemical leaveners?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are really great egg substitutes? Flax seed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much is too processed? (I’d like to keep it to things that could be made at home, if you had a reasonable set of tools, but might prefer to buy fresh from the store, e.g. Almond Milk that is only almonds and water)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you use carbonated water as a leavener? Beer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Interface to recipes</title>
   <link href="http://roughlycooking.com/2014/09/14/interface-to-recipes/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://roughlycooking.com/2014/09/14/interface-to-recipes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Simplifying communication means you can do more complicated things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most inspiring articles I ever read talks about the interface to math. The hypothesis is that math is currently harder than it could be if we rethought the interface. What does that possibly mean? Well currently we use arabic numerals and a handful of symbols to signify things. Instead of having to explain that I have two apples and that I gave them to my friend Bob who already had three in his bag and so now he has five, I can simply write: 2+3=5. And you know what that means. Which is super complicated if you think about it. The example they gave was with multiplication - Roman numerals are notoriously difficult to multiply. Before math as we know it, normal people couldn’t multiply. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was a long story to something that I am very interested in. What if we changed the interface to communicate recipes? The typical recipe lists the ingredients and the amounts (in various units) at the top and then a bullet or paragraph explanation of how to combine the ingredients. There is some other useful info like number served and time spent, but the bulk of it is actually really hard to understand. Wait, you want me to add eggs, but to what? When? The best recipes have long headnotes or detailed descriptions, but that makes it really hard to scan. So you get people like me that have just given up on most recipes. I often will pull one up and just scan it and swap everything. I am looking for key things like ingredients, how to prep, how to combinations, and the time and temperature of how to prepare. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have this solved yet at all, but I think that there might be something interesting with base recipes, standard techniques and “responsive” recipes that scale based on either your familiarity with the techniques or if you have made it before. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive recipes? Too buzzworthy? Probably. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
